Karl Pertsch

https://kpertsch.github.io karl.pertsch@gmail.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My goal is to build intelligent agents that help humans in their everyday tasks, both in the physical and virtual world. To enable this, I am working on approaches that use large and diverse datasets of prior experience to facilitate the learning of complex, long-horizon behaviors. In my research, I explore approaches that learn world models, representations of the environment or reusable skills and transfer them to new tasks.

EDUCATION

University of Southern California, Los Angeles, CA

Ph.D. in Computer Science (Advisor: Joseph J. Lim), GPA: 4.0 / 4.0

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

Fulbright Visiting Scholar, GPA: 4.0 / 4.0

TU Dresden, Dresden, Germany

Diploma in Electrical Engineering, GPA: 4.0 / 4.0 (with distinction)

Aug 2018 - Present

Aug 2017 - Aug 2018

Sept 2012 - Aug 2017

Professional Experience

Google Brain Robotics, Mountain View, CA

May 2022 - Present

Student Researcher with Karol Hausman

- Research in robot learning from large scale robot and human video data

Facebook AI Research, Menlo Park, CA

Aug 2021 - Mar 2022

Research Intern with Akshara Rai and Dhruv Batra

- Research in robot learning from cross-domain demonstrations, e.g. from human videos

RAIL Lab, UC Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

Feb 2019 - Jul 2019

Visiting Researcher with Sergey Levine

- Research on hierarchical prediction models for visual planning

GRASP Lab, UPenn, Philadelphia, PA

Aug 2017 - May 2018

Fulbright Visiting Scholar with Kostas Daniilidis

- Research in unsupervised learning of action representations

Computer Vision Lab, TU Dresden, Germany

Apr 2017 - Aug 2017

Diploma Thesis with Carsten Rother

- Research on 6DoF object pose estimation

Institute of Automotive Engineering, TU Dresden, Germany

Apr 2016 - Jan 2017

Research Assistant with Bernard Bäker

- Research in RL for learning energy-optimal driving strategies for hybrid electric vehicles

BMW Research, Munich, Germany

Sept 2015 - Mar 2016

Research Intern with Lawrence Louis and Moritz Werling

- Research in predictive models for autonomous vehicle control

1 of 4 Karl Pertsch

Conference Papers

- [C10] Karl Pertsch, Ruta Desai, Vikash Kumar, Franziska Meier, Joseph J. Lim, Dhruv Batra, and Akshara Rai. "Cross-Domain Transfer via Semantic Skill Imitation", Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL), 2022
- [C9] Jun Yamada, Karl Pertsch, Anisha Gunjal, and Joseph J. Lim. "Task-Induced Representation Learning", International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022
- [C8] Taewook Nam, Shao-Hua Sun, Karl Pertsch, Sung Ju Hwang, and Joseph J. Lim. "Skill-based Meta-Reinforcement Learning", International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022
- [C7] Karl Pertsch, Youngwoon Lee, Yue Wu, and Joseph J. Lim. "Demonstration-Guided Reinforcement Learning with Learned Skills", Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL), 2021
- [C6] Karl Pertsch, Youngwoon Lee, and Joseph J. Lim. "Accelerating Reinforcement Learning with Learned Skill Priors", Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL), 2020
- [C5] Jun Yamada*, Youngwoon Lee*, Gautam Salhotra, Karl Pertsch, Max Pflueger, Gaurav S. Sukhatme, Joseph J. Lim, and Peter Englert. "Motion Planner Augmented Reinforcement Learning for Robot Manipulation in Obstructed Environments", Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL), 2020
- [C4] Karl Pertsch*, Oleh Rybkin*, Frederik Ebert, Chelsea Finn, Dinesh Jayaraman, and Sergey Levine. "Long-Horizon Visual Planning with Goal-Conditioned Hierarchical Predictors", Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020
- [C3] Karl Pertsch*, Oleh Rybkin*, Jingyun Yang, Shenghao Zhou, Kosta Derpanis, Joseph J. Lim, Kostas Daniilidis, and Andrew Jaegle. "KeyIn: Keyframing for Visual Planning", Conference on Learning for Dynamics and Control (L4DC), 2020
- [C2] Oleh Rybkin*, Karl Pertsch*, Konstantinos G. Derpanis, Kostas Daniilidis, and Andrew Jaegle. "Learning what you can do before doing anything", International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2019
- [C1] Omid Hosseini Jafari*, Siva Karthik Mustikovela*, Karl Pertsch, Eric Brachmann, and Carsten Rother. "iPose: Instance-Aware 6D Pose Estimation of Partly Occluded Objects", Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV), 2018

TECHNICAL REPORTS

- [T4] Shivin Dass*, Karl Pertsch*, Hejia Zhang, Youngwoon Lee, Joseph J. Lim, and Stefanos Nikolaidis. "Assisted Teleoperation for Scalable Robot Data Collection", CoRL Workshop on Pretraining Robot Learning, 2022
- [T3] Anthony Liang, Ishika Singh, **Karl Pertsch**, and Jesse Thomason. "Transformer Adapters for Robot Learning", CoRL Workshop on Pretraining Robot Learning, 2022
- [T2] Jesse Zhang*, Karl Pertsch*, Jiahui Zhang, Taewook Nam, Sung Ju Hwang, Xiang Ren, and Joseph J. Lim. "Scalable Semantic Policy Pre-Training via Language Instruction Relabeling", CoRL Workshop on Language in RL, 2022
- [T1] Jesse Zhang*, Karl Pertsch*, Jiefan Yang, and Joseph J. Lim. "Minimum Description Length Skills for Accelerating Reinforcement Learning", NeurIPS Workshop on Self-Supervised Learning in RL, 2021

2 of 4 Karl Pertsch

HONORS	AND	Awards
HONORD	AND	INMILLO

Honors and Awards	
• Best Paper Presentation Award, CoRL	2020
• Best Paper Runner-up, NeurIPS Workshop on Robot Lea	arning 2020
• Fulbright Scholarship	2017
• TU Dresden Best Diploma in Electrical Engineering Awa	ard 2017
• TU Dresden Best Pre-Diploma Award	2014
• Deutschlandstipendium - German national scholarship for outstanding academic	$2013 - 2017 \\ achievements$
Invited Talks	
Accelerating Reinforcement Learning and Imitation	
• MILA, Invited talk in Glen Berseth's lab	Nov 2022
A Scalable Framework for Skill-based Learning with	h Offline Data
• Stanford University, Invited talk at Vision & Learning La	
• University of Pennsylvania, Invited talk at PAL Lab	Jun 2021
TEACHING	
Teaching Assistant, USC CSCI-566 Deep Learning and its Application (Joseph J. Lin	Spring 2019, Fall 2019, Fall 2020 m)
Teaching Assistant, TU Dresden Department of Electrical Engineering General Tutoring	Spring 2016, Fall 2016
Teaching Assistant, TU Dresden Math 1 & 2 for Electrical Engineering (Jörg Wensch)	Fall 2014, Spring 2015
STUDENT MENTORING	
Ph.D. Students	
• Jesse Zhang (USC)	${\bf Language + Skills~in~RL~(in\text{-}progress)}$
• Anthony Liang (USC)	Language in RL (in-progress)
• Taewook Nam (KAIST)	ICLR 2022
Master's Students	
• Shivin Dass (USC)	Robot Teleoperation (in-progress)
• Jullian Yapeter (USC)	Deep Reinforcement Learning (in-progress)
Undergraduate Students	
• Yue Wu (USC)	CoRL 2021
• Jingyun Yang (USC \rightarrow Master's student at CMU \rightarrow Ph.	D. student at Stanford) L4DC 2020
Visiting Scholars	

Visiting Scholars

 $\bullet\,$ Jun Yamada (USC \to Ph.D. student at Oxford)

 $\operatorname{CoRL}\ 2020,\ \operatorname{ICLR}\ 2022$

 \bullet Anisha Gunjal (USC \rightarrow M.S. student at UT Austin)

 $ICLR\ 2022$

SERVICES

Reviewer (Top Reviewer Awards $\underline{\text{Underlined}}$)

ICLR: 2020, 2021, <u>2022</u>
ICML: <u>2020</u>, <u>2021</u>, 2022

NeurIPS: 2020CoRL: 2021

• ICRA: 2021, 2022

T-RO: 2022
TMLR: 2022
ICCV: 2019
CVPR: 2019

Last Update : November 28, 2022

4 of 4 Karl Pertsch